In order to group by day,
要按天分组
we'll need to adjust all the times on April 1st 2017
我们需要将 2017-04-01 的所有时间调整为
to read: 2017-04-01 00:00:00.
2017-04-01 00:00:00 这种格式
That way when we group by date,
这样 用按天分组的方法
we get every event that occurred for all hours,
我们就能获得在 4 月 1 日这一天当中的每小时
minutes, and seconds of April 1st.
每分钟及每秒钟内出现的事件
They'll all be grouped together into the same grouping.
将所有事件分在同一组
We can do this using the date trunc function.
这可以通过 DATE_TRUNC (日期截断) 函数来完成
Let's start by grouping by occurred at without any truncation.
我们先试着不做任何截断 对 occurred_at 列进行分组
As you can see, this doesn't help us much at all.
可以看到 这对我们一点帮助都没有
If we replace each instance of occurred at with a truncated version,
如果将 occurred_at 列中的每一个实例 替换为截断后的版本
we'll get a result set that sums the quantities of standard paper by day.
我们会得到一个结果集 即标准纸数量的每日总和
It's important to group by the same metric that's included in
重要的是 GROUP BY 后的指标要包含在
the select statement to assure your results are consistent.
SELECT 语句中 以确保结果的一致性
In some databases, it's possible to group by
在某些数据库中 可能出现在 GROUP BY 语句中按年为单位进行分组
a year but truncate on day in the select statement.
但在 SELECT 语句中以天为单位进行截断
This is something most people only do by accident as it provides results that are
这种情况大多是意外出现的
confusing and in many cases wrong for the type of question you're trying to answer.
因为结果会让人困惑 而且基本上无法给出你想要的答案
The easiest way to make sure you group correctly is to
要确保分组正确 最简单的方法是
use column numbers instead of retyping the exact functions.
使用列数 而不是重新输入具体函数
Date trunc can be used to aggregate at very granular levels like second.
DATE_TRUNC 可用于聚合小单位 比如秒
That might be useful if you're working with
如果你处理服务器日志
server logs or many events happen in a given second.
或者指定的一秒中发生的事件 DATE_TRUNC 或许能帮到你
Most of the time though,
而大部分时间内
you'll use this to aggregate at intervals that make
你会从业务角度
sense from a business perspective: day,
用它进行某个时间段的聚合
week, month, quarter, and year.
每天 每周 每月 每季度以及每年
Here, we can see different truncations.
现在 我们能看到不同的截断
Notice that if our month or day are 01,
如果我们月份或日期是 01
there's no change made to these values, as you can see.
可以看到 这些值并没有任何变化
There are some cases where you might want to just pull out a given part of the day.
有些情况下 你可能会想从一天中拉取指定部分
For example, if you want to know what day of
例如 如果你想知道
the week Parch &amp; Posey's website sees the most traffic,
Parch &amp; Posey 网站周几流量最大
you wouldn't want to use date trunc.
你不会想使用 DATE_TRUNC
To get the day of the week,
要想知道是周几
you'd have to use date part.
你得用到 DATE_PART
Date part allows you to pull the part of the date that you're interested in.
通过 DATE_PART 你能提取出最感兴趣的那部分日期
But notice that regardless of year,
但应注意 由于忽略了年份
a date part would provide the same month for an event that happens in April 2016 and
DATE_PART 针对 2016 年 4 月和 2017 年 4 月发生的事件会返回相同的月份
April 2017 where a date trunc would differentiate these events.
而 DATE_TRUNC 会对两者进行区分
Let's explore this example using Parch &amp; Posey's data.
用 Parch &amp; Posey 的数据举例
On what day of the week are the most sales made?
周几的销售量最高？
Let's start by figuring out the day of the week for each one.
我们先从区分出每周的每一天开始着手
DOW stands for day of week and returns a value from zero to six,
DOW (Day of Week) 是指一周内的某天 会返回一个从 0 到 6 的值
where zero is Sunday and six is Saturday.
0 代表周日 6 代表周六
Now that we have this column,
现在可以得出这个列
we can aggregate to figure out the day with the most reams of paper sold.
我们可以通过聚合得出纸量销售量最大的日期
We'll order it by the sum in descending order so that
我们可以对总数进行降序排列
the day with the most sales will be at the top of the result set.
这样 销售量最高的那天就会在结果集的最顶端
Looks like the most paper was ordered on
看起来 销售量最高的是周日
Sunday and the least paper was ordered on Thursday.
而最低的那天是周四